(Street World Fighter: Directors' War)
(24 hours to determine 3 people's fate)
(Last Stage: 24H mission conditions)
(Complete the performance using tables and chairs.)
(This will be the last time.)
(I'm sorry. I'm being too greedy.)
(24 hours felt too long.)
(No one can beat that.)
(That's too intense.)
(Hash's going to come back alive.)
(How is that possible in 24 hours?)
(That's intense.)
(I feel like we're on the same page.)
(Who will be the only one to survive the Last Stage?)
(On September 12)
At 12pm on September 12,
Last Stage: 24H was released.
The number of choreographers who can save their names...
and return here is...
only one.
The last stage to determine your destiny.
The Last Stage.
On the Last Stage: 24H,
you'll be evaluated...
based on your directing skills, creativity, and dance.
Hello.
(That's cute.)
For me, I think the thing that excites me the most...
in this challenge...
is seeing how they utilize the props.
So it's all about how smart they can be, not just how great they can be.
Because this competition is about being a great director.
I'm so excited to see...
how these dancers utilize such a short amount of time...
and I wish them the best. Good luck.
Hello, everyone.
(Inducing cheers just by saying hi)
I was there myself last year.
I know how you feel exactly.
While I'm rooting for you,
I want to judge you fairly.
They're already experts in directing.
So I'm going to focus more on your dance skills...
and how impressive it is.
That's what I'm going to see.
Good luck, everyone.
The first choreographer of the Last Stage.
It's Renan.
Let's go, Renan!
(The first choreographer on the Last Stage is Renan.)
She wasn't wearing socks.
I could see her determination.
(Full of...)
(expectations)
(Spotting)
(The choreographers spot something.)
That's scary.
My gosh.
She even drew Xs on their faces.
She drew curse signs on their faces.
It feels like a horror movie.
It's scary.
I am looking forward to watching her performance.
Interesting.
The concept of my Last Stage is...
the dark side I've gone through...
while on this show.
I decided to express that in the intro.
The pressure to win.
The stress from competition and anxiety.
That's what I wanted to express.
I recorded it in Japanese.
(I shed endless tears.)
(And I faced my limit.)
(Guilty Pleasure, Advanced, Brian U)
Then the source suddenly begins...
along with the nightmare.
I wanted to make something using chairs.
I wanted to express my emotion...
and the darkness inside me by moving the chairs.
And the dancers were standing in a grotesque position like ghosts.
If I create a horror movie with wow factors,
it'll be fun to watch.
Let's go.
You got this!
Keep it up.
- You got this!
- Good luck.
She's starting.
(Groaning)
She must be nervous.
I wanted her to do well, so I rooted for her.
I expected Renan's performance to be a game changer.
I couldn't wait to see it.
(A performance that reflects the emotions she had while dancing)
(The tables and chairs are used as an individual rather than objects.)
(Performance by Team Renan)
It's going to be great.
(Exclaiming)
(Focusing)
I love it.
She really gritted her teeth.
Renan's really determined.
It's so tense.
- Wait. What is that?
- My goodness.
(Surprised)
- That's scary.
- I know.
It's like a horror movie.
I was expecting something creepy.
(Shocked)
Oh, my gosh.
Wait.
- Oh, my gosh.
Oh, my gosh.
That's crazy.
- Awesome.
- Let's go.
That's amazing.
That's so cool.
(Exclaiming)
(Perfect)
She's using lasers.
It's unbelievable.
It's a good idea to use the lasers.
Nice.
(Exclaiming)
Let's go.
(Team Renan's dancers: Kim Min Seo, Na Yeong, Kim Jung Won, Kim Ji Woo)
(Ha Jung In, Jung Ki Jung, Jang Jung Eum, Koo Min Seo)
She made that in only 24 hours?
That's really amazing.
- Good job.
- I did it.
I pulled off the things I thought were impossible.
It felt so relieving.
(She nailed it.)
(Renan is the best.)
The next choreographer is...
JEONG MIN JUN.
(The next person on stage is JEONG MIN JUN.)
MIN JUN.
(Go, MIN JUN.)
(JEONG MIN JUN appears flapping the robe.)
What's the concept of this performance?
It's inspired...
by Hungnam evacuation from the movie, "Ode to My Father."
- Sean, do you know the movie?
- Yes?
Oh, yes. I saw it long time ago.
Is it an old movie?
It appeared in the beginning of "Ode to My Father."
I decided to direct...
what happened while people were evacuating during the Korean War.
They were withdrawing.
I might also have to withdraw after this stage.
So I wanted to show them.
(Spotting...)
(something)
(They're flipping the table.)
I loved his idea.
MIN JUN is such a genius.
I think that nailed it.
(The judges carefully watch them setting up the objects.)
(Looking forward)
Interesting.
I like it.
Since it's inspired by the Hungnam evacuation,
I decided to flip the table and make it a ship.
I knew no one thought of...
flipping the tables.
That'll be my strength.
I'll make it look like a ship by flipping the table.
Then I made a bow with chairs.
And I only used the members of The Stories...
who are on my team as my dancers.
There's a distance between us...
because I'm not able to participate in the team due to the show.
As if I'm waiting for the day we unite again.
I set it up to show the situation.
It looks like a real ship.
The evacuation operation of The Stories.
I couldn't stop exclaiming.
I wanted to shock everyone.
I wanted to show I was on another level.
They won't be able to eliminate me after watching this.
I'm confident. I'll survive.
JEONG MIN JUN's last directing stage.
Show them, MIN JUN.
- Let's go.
- You got this.
You got this.
You guys, ready?
Fight.
(Motivated by the Hungnam evacuation from "Ode to My Father")
(Framing a ship by flipping the 10m-long table)
(Performance by Team JEONG MIN JUN)
(Paying attention)
(In awe)
Nice.
(Exclaiming)
(Surprised)
(Interesting)
(That's insane.)
(Exclaiming)
(Goosebumps)
(Applauding automatically)
(Loving it)
It's insane.
They're in perfect sync.
(Exclaiming)
(That's right.)
(This is it.)
The quality of his show was insane.
This isn't going to be easy.
(Exclaiming)
That looks like water.
Their dancing is...
(Jumping off from the ship?)
(Good job!)
(Enchanted)
I was in despair.
- Awesome.
- That's terrific.
(That dancing is crazy.)
That's amazing.
(Immersed)
(Overwhelmed)
(Marvelous)
(Nervous, anxious)
I love it.
That looks like a real ship.
(Overwhelmed)
(Focused)
(Immersed)
(Only the sound of smoke...)
(echoes on stage...)
(like the sound of waves.)
Someone has to send them applause.
(As soon as people hear clapping,)
(they start sending applause and cheers.)
- Amazing.
- Did you see that?
That was terrific.
Honey J is crying.
(JEONG MIN JUN's performance was touching enough to make people cry.)
I'm crying.
(She wipes her tears.)
(But she can't possibly calm down despite the applause.)
Amazing.
Yes.
He loves it. Sean Lew loves it.
His directing was perfect.
I watched Sean Lew. He did this a lot.
He shot a lot.
The last choreographer for the Last Stage is...
Hash.
(Last Stage: 24H)
(Full of...)
(cheers)
You can do it!
Yes, Hash. Let's go.
You got this.
She didn't wear socks again.
I knew she was bringing out her signature move.
I could tell that she really gritted her teeth.
Hash.
What's the concept of this performance?
First of all, the theme of this music is...
the new generation.
Through this performance,
I want to open a new chapter of my life.
That's how I want this to be remembered.
I wanted to express that through my dance.
Through my own dance.
To survive,
and to prove her directing skills,
she put her reputation on the line to prepare this final performance.
It begins now.
Let's go.
You guys ready?
Fight.
(Last Stage: 24H)
(You got this.)
- Let's go.
- You can do it.
(Director Hash)
(The theme is the new generation.)
(Separating the space on stage by using the objects)
These 30 people must be different.
It's like they're in a contest.
I can't wait.
Hash's so dogged right now.
(Performance by Team Hash)
(Awesome)
(Cheering)
(Focused)
(Eyes focused)
(Shaking his head)
I'm getting goosebumps.
I didn't see that coming.
(Shocked)
(Surprised)
(Cheering)
Hash, let's go!
That's her style.
(Surprised)
x
(That's legendary.)
(Surprised)
Good job.
The table's going up.
(Immersed)
How are they keeping the heavy table up?
Hey.
So that's how it goes.
(Fascinated)
(Loving it)
(Thrilled)
Good job. That's awesome!
(Please.)
(She nailed it.)
I like that part.
(Completely immersed)
(Shocked)
The judges might like Hash's performance.
That's wonderful.
(Team Hash's dancers: Lee Ha Yeon, Lee Hyun Seung, Oh Ye Rin)
(Hong Yun Jee, Song Min Chae, Kim Dong Hee, Oh Se Eun, Lee Su Jin)
(Lee Yun Ah, Choi Seo Bin, Lim Hyo Su, Yun Dong Hyun)
(Applauding)
(Oh, my gosh.)
Don't cry.
(Already addicted)
(In shock)
(In love)
Gosh.
It's a matter of taking a risk...
or staying safe...
in 24 hours.
I think that determines it.
Yes. Reason, story, emotion.
Cleanliness. So...
I feel like...
- we're on the same page?
- Yes.
I will announce the choreographer who got eliminated first.
Oh, no.
Oh, my gosh.
Today, we fight judges...
didn't evaluate on who's the better choreographer,
but who was more persuasive...
in terms of proving their directing skills.
As a result,
the first choreographer to be eliminated is...
Renan.
(The first eliminated choreographer is Renan.)
Some cases, the story is stronger than the prop.
Then the prop was stronger than the story.
But I feel like in her case,
the story and the prop were a little weak.
And in terms of order, I'd probably put...
Renan last.
Yes.
JEONG MIN JUN.
Hash.
I will announce the choreographer who survived.
Honey J.
Please announce it.
We fight judges...
evaluated based on...
the quality of the work, the use of the object,
and how persuasive the concept was.
As a result,
only one choreographer...
demonstrated directing skills...
convincingly.
The survivor who will join in the next mission is...
I think I'm going to win.
I want to survive.
The survivor who will join in the next mission is...
(Last Stage: 24H)
JEONG MIN JUN.
Congratulations.
(JEONG MIN JUN survives.)
(Hash got eliminated.)
(The eliminated choreographer, Hash)
Hash was good,
but it wasn't distinctive enough.
I think what if Hash just used the wall...
or the table for a reason,
like what if that wall was stopping her from something...
I think it just was a wall for no reason.
- MIN JUN had everything.
- That's right.
Reason, story, emotion.
Quality.
He hit all the marks, so...
MIN JUN.
Congratulations.
Well done.
Good job.
I'm not sure whether I should clap or not.
(You can watch their full video on "The CHOOM" and "Mnet Plus.")
(The night after the Last Stage)
(Feeling heavy-hearted about leave)
(Renan gets ready to leave.)
- Renan.
- Hey.
(The choreographers are here to say goodbye.)
Renan.
Sit down.
Let's talk. It's been a while.
I'm scared.
You did well.
- No.
- Well done.
You all did well.
You can be less hard on yourself.
You're already talented enough.
Believe in yourself.
I could've just had fun,
but I couldn't do that just like her.
(The light in Renan's room went off every time she had a hard time.)
You were alone in the dark.
Whenever I turned my head,
I could see you pulled your hat down to your lips.
That's what I saw all the time.
When things don't go well,
I can't forgive myself.
If something doesn't work out,
I blame myself.
You don't have to be so hard on yourself.
- Just enjoy it.
- Relax.
Just have fun. That's all you need to do.
How did you...
beat me all three times?
Seriously.
- I almost cried.
- Why?
They asked me, "How would you feel to see Hash leave?"
I said I'd do nothing but cry.
Stop making me cry.
I don't want to cry anymore.
I'm crying again.
Why am I crying?
I'm the one who's leaving.
You're on your own now.
You have to show them.
I couldn't do it.
I'll prove myself in the competition scene.
You have to prove yourself here.
(A request from the one who's leaving)
(A heaviness of the one who has to say goodbye)
You're good. I know you are.
I know it from being your rival.
You're darn strong.
How are you so strong?
I learned so much through Street World Fighter.
I got to try work, missions, and experience...
that I haven't had before.
Most importantly, I got to learn a lot...
from other directors.
"That can be a way to create a choreography."
"Gosh, that's another perspective to see it."
This show gave me a chance...
to broaden my perspective.
I'm leaving the show now.
Everything I gained and learned here...
will reflect in my growth forward.
I'll continue to work hard...
and prove myself.
Please look forward to my improvement.
(Hash leaves the Director's Room after leaving her last message.)
Through this show,
I've become a better choreographer and a better director.
Please look forward to my highlights.
I am Director Renan.
(Renan leaves the Director's Room where she laughed and cried.)
(New morning arrives after two directors leave.)
I have sad news as soon as I'm here.
This is sad.
She wrote a message for everyone.
It's touching.
"Thank you for leading us..."
"during the Director's Cut."
"Since the first signature choreography match,"
"you were the only one who took my side,"
"and you've always been very supportive."
I'm glad this experience left them...
good memories.
This is why I don't get close to people.
We finally became close,
but their rooms are closed.
And the lights are off.
This is heartbreaking.
I mean it.
I'll cherish this letter.
Two people are gone out of ten.
It feels really empty.
(2 Director's Rooms are shut.)
(And one Director's Room is still empty.)
I'm back.
How do I feel? I did everything I could to come back.
It's a lot of pressure.
Renan on one shoulder and Hash on the other.
(Screaming)
I bet other people were afraid...
after seeing my performance.
"He's dangerous."
I bet that's how other people felt.
Now that I'm back,
I'll shock the other choreographers...
into thinking that I'm a strong candidate to win.
("Royalty" by Yoon Mi Rae and Tiger JK)
(K-pop Solo Artist Direct Mission)
(Nice!)
(It's time to do my job.)
(2:2 Duet Match)
(BAILEY match)
(TAEYONG match)
(All 4 choreographers from the losing team...)
(will head straight to the Last Stage: 24H.)
(Screaming)
(If I lose, it's the Last Stage.)
(I'm going to send everyone to the Last Stage.)
(I must win no matter what.)
I need to get everyone involved.
(BAILEY match)
(No one's willing to yield.)
(JEONG MIN JUN and Kasper's choreography shoot)
(JEONG MIN JUN has trouble directing.)
(It's frustrating, to be honest.)
(There is not a single thing that I like so far.)
(What do you want then?)
(Who will TAEYONG...)
(Who will BAILEY...)
(Which team will the solo artist choose?)
- Hello.
Hello.
(8 choreographers gather in the Directors' Lab.)
Why is everyone calm?
Perhaps because two people are gone?
All I'm thinking about is avoiding the Last Stage.
Absolutely.
There will be a new mission today, right?
What are we doing today?
Tell us already.
Film, stage... K-pop?
Is it a mega mission?
That's absurd.
Who said no?
(Diverse speculations rise along with the memories.)
I don't even know what we're doing next.
(What's going to happen today?)
What's happening? Tell me already.
Oh, I don't know. I'm just going to lie down.
The competition that started with ten people...
(Startled)
- The competition...
- My goodness.
The competition that started with ten people...
has now narrowed down to eight choreographers...
who will continue the directing battle.
Here we go.
It's the next mission.
The next mission is...
(K-pop Solo Artist Direct Mission)
the K-pop Solo Artist Direct Mission.
- What?
Gosh.
The choreographers will direct a male solo artist...
and a female solo artist.
The completed work will...
become their official performance...
in September.
Nice.
It's a chance for me to do my job. Oh, my gosh.
This is going to be fun.
Awesome. That's going to be so much fun.
It's time to do my job.
We get to give the situation and story to the artist.
We choose their characters on stage,
set the theme, and shape their identity.
And we lead them.
Simply put, we decide everything from head to toe.
That's exactly what I'm doing.
It's meant for me.
It's made for me.
I couldn't be more confident.
The production crew got me what I'm good at.
I might as well accept it.
It's one's ability to seize the opportunity, right?
I'm confident.
Because it's a K-pop mission.
(While everyone is confident,)
(only one Director's Room is quiet.)
What am I going to do?
I've never done K-pop before.
If I were to do it, I could.
It'll be a nice experience.
Still, I have no idea what to do.
The two solo artists who will be performing.
Here they are.
Who are they?
(Male solo artist)
(SM Entertainment, Fight Judge, global male group)
A fight judge?
Who was here as a fight judge?
Is it Eunhyuk?
That's Eunhyuk.
SM Entertainment's global group who was here as a fight judge...
Eunhyuk?
A fight judge.
A global male group. TAEYONG.
It's got to be TAEYONG.
He was the fight judge in Season One.
(Is TAEYONG the male solo artist?)
I hope it's TAEYONG.
I recently worked with him.
I know exactly...
what he likes...
and what he pursues.
Please.
Is it TAEYONG?
(The artist's guide track is finally revealed.)
(Smiling)
It's him! Right?
It's TAEYONG!
(Excited)
It must be TAEYONG.
I bet it's TAEYONG.
(He can't help but dance.)
The song...
I thought this was a song you could physically collide with.
I figured I could capture...
my own style in this.
It sounds cool.
It's an aggressive track that feels like...
the performance would stick to it perfectly.
I like it. It's good,
but the concept will need to be executed really well.
If you just the concept entirely around the song's vibe,
we all will end up looking similar,
so it will need a unique angle.
The track is great, but I've never taken charge...
of a male solo artist before,
so I'm curious about the female solo artist.
(Female solo artist)
(Kinjaz, W-D, THE -LACKLABEL)
(Shouting)
(Explosive reaction)
The second I saw Kinjaz, I knew immediately.
Even without the other keywords, I know for sure.
BAILEY is...
literally the only intersection...
among these three.
(Then is the female solo artist BAILEY?)
BAILEY. Bailey Sok
I know her so well.
We've even collaborated on choreography before.
I probably have the deepest understanding of her.
I'm curious about the track.
The song has to be good, though.
Please.
(The female solo artist's guide track is revealed.)
I'm going with this one.
This is it!
(This is it!)
She's going crazy over there. She bubbles over with joy.
I'm so excited!
Regardless of how it goes, I just love it so much.
It has a kind of heavy, deep vibe.
This kind of deep, slightly minor vibe...
is something...
I can pull off really well.
Musically, this one is...
definitely much closer to what I prefer.
It's totally my style.
It has many intricate sounds...
that I really want to experiment with,
so I want it so badly.
The song is tricky, though.
Rather than having an easy hook,
it feels like you have to keep dancing non-stop.
The choreography will be crucial.
(The choreography looks to be the deciding factor for this track.)
Although this mission involves...
directing a solo artist,
the choreographers will not be competing alone.
Street World Fighter: Directors' War's...
first team battle.
(2:2 Duet Match)
The 2-on-2 Duet Match.
Nice!
(Celebrating it in joy)
I love it.
I figured there would be a team mission at least once.
I like it.
This was a pairing format...
I really wanted to try.
The 2-on-2 duet match.
The eight choreographers...
will pair up into teams of two...
to direct each solo artist.
Starting now,
choreographers will personally choose the partner...
they will execute the mission with.
- Okay.
- Those who finalize their teams...
must register their names...
on the registration board in the center of the stage,
and only registered pairs...
will be recognized as official teams.
Furthermore, once the quota is filled,
that specific artist can no longer be chosen.
We have to move fast.
The result of this mission...
directly links to survival.
All four choreographers who win their matches...
(The winners survive.)
will survive.
All four choreographers on the losing teams...
will go straight to the Last Stage: 24H.
I didn't know I'd be hearing that again.
Why are you sending four whole people?
That means a 50-50 chance.
So we have no choice but to win.
If I lose, I go straight to the Last Stage.
I really need to choose my team wisely.
I need to find...
an absolute winning member.
I have to pick someone who won't end up in the Last Stage.
I need to settle this immediately...
and get our names up on that registration board quickly.
Avoiding the Last Stage is the smartest move.
Who would want to team up with me for a K-pop mission?
Probably no one.
If you want to win, you have to take me.
If you're looking for a winning teammate, it's me.
I'm winning this time, no matter what.
Got it?
I'm the best...
at the NEO vibe out of everyone here.
You know I do this kind of stuff better than anyone.
The time has finally come for me to show my true worth.
I've made up my mind.
I'm going with TAEYONG's track.
I need to choose something I can execute better...
and something I can whip up quickly and make look tasty.
Someone TAEYONG would vibe with.
It's NaiN.
NaiN worked with TAEYONG most recently, after all.
Gosh.
(BADA's desired teammate: NaiN)
BADA picks me.
(NaiN, please accept my heart.)
(Is NaiN's choice BADA as well?)
I think I'm going with the male artist now.
Then shouldn't I team up with NaiN,
who's been my rival all this time?
I have to win no matter what.
That's why I thought NaiN and I had to join forces.
But what if NaiN doesn't take me?
I feel like she might go to Kasper or INGYOO.
Please.
NaiN!
(Desperate BABYZOO)
Seriously.
NaiN, you know why...
our projects overlap so much, don't you?
NaiN, I'm right here!
NaiN!
I really want to do BAILEY's track.
First off...
Simeez?
I thought Simeez was the only one...
who could bring out the feminine vibe.
She's someone who can compensate...
for what you might call my slight weaknesses.
(Flapping)
(A performance to win her over)
(Gestures trying to win over Simeez)
(She has no idea.)
(While Kasper sends out his love signals)
I think teaming up with Simeez makes the most sense.
Since I never want to end up in the Last Stage,
wouldn't it be best to pair up with Simeez,
where our synergy would clearly pop?
She's been handling IVE...
right from the pre-production stage, and tapping into that experience
while setting a solid concept and tone...
would make our work convincing.
I'm just praying Simeez feels the same way.
(Another heart signal)
(INGYOO's desired teammate: Simeez)
(Who wants to team up with me?)
I think I'll team up with INGYOO.
INGYOO just sent me a signal.
Hang on.
It looks like Kasper is also sending a signal.
Or am I imagining things?
I locked eyes with both INGYOO and Kasper.
Now...
(Two men are sending desperate signals toward Simeez.)
They both are... Maybe I'm wrong.
If I have to choose, that's kind of tough for me.
(Who will be the teammate to join Simeez?)
Are you sending signals now?
(Thinking)
Would anyone even want to team up with me?
I'm such an old-timer.
I'm kind of an old head, you know?
So...
(An old head)
Would any of them actually want to work with me?
Should I just pair up with whoever's left?
Let's say MIN JUN and I are left. Even if I team up with him,
I'm still confident.
I need to team up with INGYOO.
They are only going to try pairing up with frontrunners,
so I think I need to claim him first...
and block his way.
I have to win this mission.
I don't want to go to the Last Stage ever again.
I should sprint straight to INGYOO...
and tell him to do BAILEY's track with me.
I'll drag him along like this.
Then let me get ready to dash out,
since I have to be the first one sprinting.
(Warming up)
Everyone is ready to sprint right now.
When is the siren going off?
It usually goes off so fast. Why is it taking forever today?
Isn't NaiN at an advantage?
Isn't she too close to the registration board?
I'm going to sprint really fast.
(Team selection starts!)
(Simeez rushes out.)
Is it now?
(I have to hurry.)
(All 8 choreographers sprint out at full speed.)
(Got you!)
Even if it means kidnapping INGYOO, I have to drag him over.
There was only one path. BAILEY was the only option for me.
(Full sprint)
What?
- Should we do this one?
- Right?
NaiN, do you want to team up with me?
NaiN, put your name on it!
(This is not finalized yet.)
Let's do this together.
(Hesitant)
- Let's do it.
- No.
No. That's not it.
Hurry!
(Stopping him urgently)
You have to form the team before sticking the names on.
Did you guys already form a team?
Wait, aren't you supposed to form the team first?
Right. We need to talk it out.
Exactly, talk first.
Let's go back in.
- What?
- We need to talk first.
We need to talk.
I'm the first one to enter.
Honestly, it makes the most sense that we team up.
(Thinking)
I think this is the right moment for us to join forces.
It's time to show them what we've got.
(My goodness.)
What do we do?
People with great aesthetic sense need to stick together.
For now,
my first choice is Simeez.
(Come here.)
He's calling for me.
I should go crash this conversation.
- Could we talk for just a second?
- Okay.
Let's talk in a bit, too.
Well...
Even though Simeez was already with INGYOO,
with the mindset of "it never hurts to give it a shot,"
I asked to talk to Simeez.
Kasper is someone...
who studied BAILEY inside out, too.
(I'm confident, too.)
- You don't even need to explain?
- Why?
What do I do?
INGYOO was talking with Simeez for quite a while.
I thought, "His mind is already made up."
"There's no way I can turn him around."
Stalling for time here would be fatal.
NaiN, you know why our projects...
- overlap so much, don't you?
- I also think...
there's a good reason people keep calling us together.
If you want to unlock that synergy, you have to team up with me.
I'll make sure that synergy pays off.
(Approaching)
How about taking on BAILEY with me?
She's my favorite.
Would you like to team up with me?
(Torn)
My goodness. But...
BAILEY?
NaiN.
What will you do?
What do you want to do?
BABYZOO, what are you leaning toward?
- NaiN. Let's talk for a second.
- Okay.
Let's head over this way, then.
- MIN JUN? Okay.
- But, MIN JUN,
I feel like I have to do TAEYONG's track.
- Do you not mind?
- It doesn't matter.
MIN JUN.
I wanted to work with NaiN,
but the moment she went straight to BABYZOO,
it seemed like her mind was already set,
so my focus shifted immediately.
I was worried...
because they are the ones doing a lot of projects lately,
whereas I'm from the generation whose work has dwindled down.
I thought it might feel burdensome...
if I ask them to team up with me first.
So I figured I should just wait a bit.
Do you feel like you'd need me?
BABYZOO is actually my first choice.
I will head straight to BABYZOO the second I step out.
The thing is, our strengths are distinctly different.
He's really good at the things I fall short in.
I think he excels at building unique formations...
and crafting flashy visual pictures...
using dancers.
So I had BABYZOO in mind from the very start.
All right.
(Feeling bitter)
Since I have zero K-pop experience,
I'm pretty much the odd one out.
Feeling like nobody wanted me was so heartbreaking.
Do you want to team up with me?
(Well...)
Can you wait? I need to think.
I'm sorry.
He doesn't have much K-pop experience.
This isn't just about tossing out ideas.
It's a battle to get your choreo picked.
With my own neck on the line,
it's tough to hold someone's hand and spoon-feed them through this.
I wanted to pour my heart into doing well,
but this massive wall called K-pop blocked my way.
What can I actually bring to the table?
(Heavy-hearted)
Koo Young was standing right there, all by himself.
So I thought I had to do this with him.
Do you want to head to a room and chat?
He's a director with an insane career history.
For 24 years?
His career spans longer than my actual age.
When it comes to sheer experience, no one can beat him.
I have to team up with him, no matter what.
I need to talk this through with Koo Young.
Personally, working on the Title Sequence Film Mission...
made me realize our dance styles spark...
- incredible synergy, - Right.
which is why I want to work with you.
To be honest,
(Chuckling)
you're my favorite.
- Then...
- I don't care about anything...
as long as I'm with you.
Even if I get eliminated, it won't matter.
Ever since I joined this survival show,
I have always wanted to collaborate with Koo Young at least once,
and I felt it would be so much fun.
I'd be thrilled if you joined me.
I'm serious.
I mean it. I'm being serious.
Thankfully, BADA extended her hand,
and there is immense trust, credibility,
and effortless chemistry between us.
Teaming up with her is amazing for me too.
Their conversation is dragging on.
It looks like Kasper is desperate.
- This is driving me crazy.
- Just do it with me.
I assumed you were going for TAEYONG's track.
I know what BAILEY needs,
and I know the exact extent of her skill set.
Besides, I've directed the most solo artists out of anyone here.
Right?
I'm not scrambling to find someone just to win...
and dodge the Last Stage.
I simply want to do this with you.
Honestly, I love them both.
I was torn.
If not me, who else are you going to team up with?
If you're not in, I'll do it by myself.
I think I was conflicted.
I mean, there's no one here...
I want to work with besides you.
(You're the only one.)
This is driving me crazy.
I thought Simeez was the only one.
Kasper has a lot of experience directing solo artists...
and knows BAILEY so well...
that he could elevate her performance.
Meanwhile, INGYOO can pinpoint an artist's peak potential so well.
So I was agonizing over it.
What did she say?
- I should head in.
- She's hesitating.
Simeez was the only person on my mind.
Because I was desperate too.
I figured she might want me.
(What is Simeez's choice?)
Well, as for us...
You guys look pretty rock-solid.
We've made up our minds.
(NaiN and BABYZOO)
(They selected the male solo artist.)
- BABYZOO!
- NaiN! Let's show them.
I'm finally teaming up with you.
I know. We're finally on the same team.
I have a good feeling right now.
- We'll never go to the Last Stage.
- Of course not.
Where are you sticking your name? TAEYONG?
I don't want to go against Koo Young and BADA.
Wouldn't Koo Young head over to TAEYONG?
I wanted to avoid them.
(Those who choose the male solo artist slot...)
(will go against NaiN and BABYZOO.)
Let's go!
(BADA and Back Koo Young)
(They selected the male solo artist.)
Just as expected, BADA and Koo Young stuck their names.
It's going to be tough,
but now is our only chance to take down Koo Young and BADA.
(Solo Artist Direct Mission, Male Artist)
What are we going to do?
Hey. Just team up with me.
This is torture.
I still haven't decided between the two. It's hard.
I really hope she chooses me.
She seemed torn,
but I predicted the answer would be obvious.
(Team up with me.)
(Studying his face)
I'm going with INGYOO. I'm so sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Rather than bouncing ideas back and forth,
Kasper tends to work entirely under his own direct lead.
So I had no choice but to go with someone...
whose working style aligns better with mine.
Okay.
- I'm really sorry.
- My goodness.
(JEONG MIN JUN and Kasper: Female solo artist)
(Solo Artist Direct Mission Female Artist)
With Kasper's experience,
he and MIN JUN will click really well.
- Do you trust me?
- Sure. Do you trust me?
(Of course.)
It wasn't the result I wanted.
I think I felt a bit pathetic about myself.
The two remaining people.
I don't think they recognize what I bring to the table.
But it's hard to take them lightly.
Kasper has plenty of experience.
The ones who looked the most like seasoned directors chose BAILEY.
I will send Kasper and MIN JUN to the Last Stage.
It is what it is.
It's about time for Kasper to experience it.
The unchosen ones.
A team forged by Nature.
This isn't a team made by our own will.
Nature brought us together. It's Season Two.
I think it was a moment I was humiliated by my abilities.
I feel like crying.
(Without fail, the siren blares across the Directors' Square.)
I was pleased to get to collaborate with NaiN.
I was so thrilled to team up with INGYOO.
(A warm atmosphere fills the Square after the duet pairings are set.)
(But MIN JUN's chair sits empty.)
(Glancing over)
I felt so small.
I think I felt a bit pathetic about myself.
Everyone else has so much experience...
- Yes!
- and radiates confidence.
but since I lack K-pop experience,
I wondered what I could bring to the table in this mission.
I didn't want to become dead weight to Kasper.
I was worried I'd just be a burden.
No. Seriously, don't worry about it.
Just trust me and follow my lead.
I can tell you what you're capable of...
and exactly what you need to do.
And...
MIN JUN might lack K-pop experience right now,
but I believed he had his own strengths.
You can't always be great from the start.
If I were in a dance competition, I wouldn't do as well as MIN JUN.
Thankfully, I felt relieved.
I had so many worries weighing on me.
Kasper has a long career and tons of experience.
It was a huge help back then.
For now, we just have to put in the work no matter what.
This is terrifying.
This is scary.
- The silence is even scarier.
- That's what makes them scarier.
I'm terrified of these two.
I looked into their eyes, and they were ashen.
They were filled with resentment.
It looked like he was about to summon a spirit.
The spirit has entered him.
MIN JUN literally...
walked back from the brink of death.
Would it even be fun watching him go back to the Last Stage?
Watching Simeez and INGYOO get sent to the Last Stage here...
will be the truly entertaining picture.
Please say something.
I'm just back from the Last Stage, so I've got venom in me now.
- My goodness.
- I'm scared.
I'm beating Simeez and INGYOO no matter what...
and dragging them all down to the Last Stage.
Please, go get a taste of that bitter pill yourselves.
Don't even ask me. I have no intention of going.
I desperately wanted to avoid the Last Stage,
and I'm going to claw my way to a win this time.
I want a complete victory.
We absolutely cannot go to the Last Stage.
It's brutal over there.
Hee Jung's heart is feeling heavy now.
She's kind of famous for being BAILEY's lookalike.
- Right.
- Hee Jung is?
A lot of people say she looks like BAILEY.
I feel like you'd be on BAILEY's visual mood board.
- What? Me?
- Yes.
I get that a lot.
Hey!
My gosh. What's that?
(Startled)
(Shocked)
What? It's amazing!
(Thrilled)
Unbelievable!
Hey!
My gosh. What's that?
(Startled)
(Shocked)
I was really surprised.
(Some people show up.)
(TAEYONG of NCT)
(BAILEY of ALLDAY PROJECT)
I'm really shocked.
I didn't expect them to show up.
I was so surprised to see them.
(Glad)
(Amazed)
(The artists for the mission: TAEYONG and BAILEY)
I felt the endorphins kick in.
Hello.
I'm TAEYONG, here to join you for the Solo Artist Direct Mission.
(TAEYONG: The solo artist whom the choreographers will direct)
He has dancing skills that professional dancers acknowledge.
He really pulls off the NEO vibe, too.
TAEYONG has a distinct color that's entirely his own.
Someone who knows how to carry style.
It was so surreal...
because it felt like watching TAEYONG of NCT right off the screen.
He was just so cool.
I only had eyes for BAILEY.
Her visual style in itself is something I love so much.
- I know.
- She looked so cool...
and striking.
You could definitely feel that true artist aura from her.
Hello. I'm BAILEY.
When people think of Kinjaz, who else comes to mind?
It's definitely BAILEY.
She competed...
on the WOD at age 14.
And at 16, she choreographed Red Velvet.
Her resume alone is already on a completely different level.
Her track record is truly unmatched in scale.
I think Bailey is an artist who can always take it further.
She's truly one of a kind,
a unique character in K-pop.
I am truly so honored to be here.
I'm so excited.
I'm a big fan of all of you guys.
So I'm more than grateful to be here.
I look forward to working with you.
(We are looking forward to it more.)
For this comeback, I want to show a new side of myself.
So beyond making choreography, I see this as a mission...
about how to direct...
and present the performance.
I'm really looking forward to it.
I look forward to working with you.
(Excited)
My first representation of myself...
as a solo artist.
So...
shall we hear it?
Yes!
This is "Can't Kill Me."
("Can't Kill Me" by Bailey)
"Can't Kill Me."
(Thrilled)
I liked it because the song itself fits my style.
It has a sexy feel too.
I love the intro.
First of all, the quality is great.
It's dark and slightly grotesque...
but it has this dangerously feminine edge.
I was glad Simeez could fill that feminine side for us.
But MIN JUN and Kasper don't have...
that feminine side covered.
But Bailey is a female artist,
and it doesn't have to be focused only on femininity.
There are endless possibilities.
I didn't think that would put me at much of a disadvantage.
That actually made me more nervous.
If Bailey really wants to show...
classic feminine choreography,
I'd be pretty worried.
I'm not familiar with it at all.
Yes! Oh, my gosh.
(The song is fire.)
Oh, my gosh!
Oh, yes!
So that was "Can't Kill Me."
From the lyrics...
to the final outro,
I made it while thinking about the performance the whole time.
Goodness.
For the performance. Crazy.
Working with Bailey taught me this more than anything.
You have to aim a hundred times...
above the usual standard.
Don't use the usual standard as your standard.
She already created next-level...
performances and choreography.
Try thinking a little differently...
and on a more global scale.
That might help.
Bailey is the kind of artist...
who directs her own performances and makes her own choreography...
and can carry it all herself as an entertainer.
Even if these two teams bring something to Bailey,
would she even like it?
I feel like Bailey already has it all in her head.
She's probably already imagining it all.
Oh, my gosh.
- Let's go!
"Wacka Wak."
(Wakanda forever)
(Dancing automatically)
This one isn't easy either.
(Getting immersed)
It's extremely intense.
I really like TAEYONG's musical style.
Maybe we can create something that feels new.
It's a rhythm I'm confident with.
NaiN and I are both great at...
making that neo kind of style...
so we absolutely have to win.
We are never going to the Last Stage.
Compared to the other team,
they may be better at masculine moves,
but BADA does manly...
better than men.
BADA is excited.
Cool and stylish...
BADA and I can do that better.
(Very satisfied)
When I made it, I really wanted...
to just cut loose.
If you don't meet our standard,
you don't even deserve to jump.
There are...
lyrics like that.
So I want you to really go all out with it.
Yes!
TAEYONG likes...
moves with flavor.
(Strongly agrees)
(INGYOO choreographed NCT U's "Baggy Jeans.")
He won't do it if it isn't cool.
But if it's too hard, he won't want to do it either.
(Flustered)
(The current choreographer agrees.)
Right.
We need to balance the difficulty.
- Easy enough, - Easy enough.
but still cool.
You know, keep it smart and clean.
And he has such a strong...
character of his own.
So if there's room to bring his character into it,
I think he'd like that.
I'll work hard on it.
Let's do this.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Goodness.
I've always been such a huge fan of Bailey.
I was even more nervous.
I think it'll be fun.
She is energetic, smart, and a super dancer.
She was already a famous dancer.
She's basically a genius.
I know her really well.
We've worked on choreography together before too.
How are you guys feeling?
- So nervous.
- Crazy.
So crazy. I'm shaking.
- Why are you shaking?
- I practiced...
everything I was going to say earlier.
You were nervous.
Solo artist comeback.
(Bailey practicing her lines)
To be doing this together...
I was on the NBC show "World of Dance"...
maybe two or three times.
But this is a Korean competition show,
so I'm in shock.
I can't remember anything.
I'm basically frozen right now.
Is this your first show like this?
My very first one.
But I'm such a huge fan.
(Proud)
That's Bailey.
(Swagger mode: ON)
I think I was probably the first...
to put her in an SM dancer lineup.
I was maybe like 15 or 16.
TAEMIN's "IDEA"...
and SHINee's "Don't Call Me."
"Don't Call Me" was choreographed by Bailey and me.
When I was dancing in the U.S,
I took classes with them.
When I was working with Kasper,
I was finding my own style.
When I really didn't know anything about the K-pop industry too.
Some of it was maybe good,
and some of it was maybe really bad.
But I think he kind of saw all of that...
and directed everything really well.
He is highly capable of seeing somebody and understanding...
them so fast
He definitely has a really great understanding of my style.
I think I'm the one who understands her strengths the best.
He has a very good understanding of Bailey,
so that made me nervous.
I need to stay sharp today.
I have an extensive experience of stage and solo artists.
- You know TAEMIN, right?
- Yes.
I worked with him for a long time and always cared about...
I was involved...
from the song camp stage.
Song camp.
I may have the most experience out of everyone here.
What?
And for a really long time,
I've hoped Bailey would debut in K-pop someday.
Really?
For a really long time. Even when we used to take...
- classes together.
- Yes.
He was already so seasoned.
I thought he was incredible.
It's my turn to make my pitch.
This is...
I started...
writing songs...
and recording them. I'm preparing my EP.
Really?
Everything I'd been thinking...
could maybe be distilled and tried here first.
I have what he's missing.
And he has what I'm missing.
We'd make the perfect team.
And we've both directed projects...
from pre-production onward.
So we know how it should be presented to the world.
It is entering the K-pop market,
but Bailey doesn't have to fit into that mold.
I want Bailey to do what Bailey wants to do...
- What I do want to know is...
- Yes.
while you were making the song,
there must be a key image that's clearly stuck in your head.
There is.
(Concentrating)
There is something.
What is it?
Can you tell us what it is?
What kind of tone does she want?
What does the artist want?
I think that's most important.
I grew up dancing hip hop with a bunch of guys.
I grew up around S-Rank and Kinjaz.
So that's what I'm comfortable in.
But at the same time,
you know, sometimes, I want to put on the heels...
That's been key for me.
I think with this song, it needs a little femininity.
I think vocally, vocal tone-wise, it kind of has...
a deep femininity to it.
With Kasper,
the feminine side is still lacking.
No one here can really do heels.
MIN JUN too doesn't have much experience yet.
I'm quite thrown off right now.
When it comes to a feminine mood,
Simeez does it better than me.
I'm actually good at that stuff.
With female solo artists,
you can't go wrong with feminine.
I'm the one who can crack that.
But...
in terms of the instruments,
it might go on a different direction.
Right.
I'll be honest.
(Listening)
As a fellow performance director,
I don't want to direct you.
Gosh.
You want to be the creative force.
When I have to choreograph a different artist,
I feel like very rarely a choreographer and director...
- in that table...
- Yes?
Like "This doesn't work."
"Do like this." You know.
That really resonated with me.
Do whatever you want.
(Do whatever you want.)
Take it as far as you want.
Whether it's like something more isolated,
or if it's something bigger,
or if it's feminine or masculine.
You're 100 percent free.
I can take my imagination all the way, with no limits.
I can do anything. "Do whatever you want."
It almost sounds unreal.
I thought the possibilities were endless.
But...
Generally,
my taste doesn't really align with the set formula.
Say yes!
I wanted to clearly avoid anything stereotypical.
Now it feels like mine.
I am confident.
Wouldn't it be fun if we won?
I have no intention of going.
I'm not going.
In a way, they're the current...
working choreographers, NaiN and BABYZOO.
So I wanted to show a little more of what I can do.
The matchup sounds so fun.
- Hello.
- Long time no see.
(They greet the artist, TAEYONG.)
Nice to see you again.
- Congrats on first place.
- Thank you.
The TAEYONG track we worked on together...
got a pretty good result.
I think that gave me confidence.
- The Young versus The Old?
- What?
Sorry.
You're right.
No, I'm sorry.
I used to get lessons...
from Koo Young.
"Mr. Back?"
Koo Young seems to have really...
mellowed out these days.
Why would you say that?
When Koo Young teaches, he only demonstrates it once.
He shows it once and says,
"Practice."
(Quick demonstration)
(Do it.)
Then I just end up standing by the mirror.
(Oh, dear.)
And that's how I produced so many great students.
Of course.
This is your first time hearing the song today, right?
- Yes.
- Did you make it?
I wrote the whole thing myself.
This place has come alive thanks to the song.
- Really? That's a relief.
- My dopamine's kicking in.
He's so fit now.
Your physique fits this vibe perfectly.
They were really selling themselves.
I'll make sure you don't regret it.
I feel a little threatened.
NaiN...
(Me?)
was never around when I was active.
She just never showed up. She's the director after all.
- I...
- She was here the whole time.
- I was here.
- I see.
She hasn't paid you much attention.
I was a little thrown off.
This time, I'm going all out.
Honestly, his style might be...
- the one style I've never tried.
- Yes.
My lines aren't naturally pretty.
So I'm a little worried.
BABYZOO already has that slight Waacking image.
That is true. My strength is my lines, after all.
But I'm just as confident...
with something more hip.
So maybe I can use that and make it work visually.
"Wacha Wak" is actually...
just a sound effect I made up.
The phrase itself doesn't really mean anything.
But if you listen to the lyrics,
the theme is bound to feel intense and flashy.
It was easier to interpret...
because the track itself...
had the same concept as "WYLD," which I made with NaiN.
For anything with that neon vibe, call NaiN and me.
So I felt more confident.
For the chorus, I wanted it to work well...
as a dance challenge.
It was game over.
I'm really good at making challenge choreography.
TAEYONG was actually the first artist...
to do my "Smoke" challenge.
Like with the "Smoke" challenge,
I think I know what TAEYONG wants...
and can make choreography that he'll think is cool.
We worked with TAEYONG recently,
so I think it's time for us to pull off an upset.
I thought we had to show it more clearly this time.
As TAEYONG's choreographer,
I want him to see why I was there,
and why Koo Young was there before.
So I'm putting even more into this mission.
Now, you'll officially begin creating your choreography.
Even though this is a team mission.
In the first creation stage,
choose a choreographer for each section.
So it's a section-by-section competition.
(Oh?)
With your concept boards and choreography draft videos...
See you on June 19 at my company's HQ.
We'll meet at SM Entertainment.
- Yes!
(Finally, the day of concept briefing...)
(and choreography draft video reveal is here.)
(I'm really looking forward to it, like genuinely.)
(Loving it)
(The structure is insane.)
(We should've made this the title track.)
(We're screwed, aren't we?)
(Signature, forehead-flick dance)
(Is it a move...)
(people would want to copy?)
(Actually,)
(a forehead-flick is a little...)
(Something new, something cool)
(That's what's important.)
(I don't want to force something...)
(just for a dance challenge.)
(The chances of having the same...)
(intro choreography are one in a million.)
(The quality is really high.)
(but from a public standpoint,)
(it doesn't have a strong hook.)
(The use of the heels is very memorable.)
(But...)
(she took the heels off...)
(and krump?)
(I don't know if it's working.)
(Which team will be chosen by TAEYONG and Bailey?)
I should go back and watch TAEYONG's performances.
("Baggy Jeans" by NCT U)
He likes hip hop.
Yes.
("SHALALA" by TAEYONG)
He really dances a lot.
He likes standout moves,
but they're unusual.
("WYLO" by TAEYONG)
NaiN's recent work.
NaiN and BABYZOO are basically...
currently active choreographers.
So I do feel a little wary.
But I've actually worked with TAEYONG a lot too.
We choreographed "ZOO" together,
worked on his solo tracks,
and even made challenges together.
I know a lot of the things...
TAEYONG tends to like.
As for TAEYONG, back when he was still a trainee...
(I used to...)
(get lessons...)
(from Mr. Back.)
("Mr. Back?")
Koo Young was cool even then. He already had his own style.
TAEYONG won't do it if it isn't cool.
But NaiN and BABYZOO have such beautiful lines.
So I do wonder if that kind of pretty movement fits this song.
We're still better at more masculine movement.
We're going to compete with solidity and strength.
NaiN and BABYZOO are basically currently active choreographers now.
So I want him to understand why I was there before,
and why Koo Young was there.
I think that's different from NaiN and BABYZOO...
who only met him recently.
It's time to bring back TAEYONG's dance nostalgia.
But we still have to live in the present.
Wouldn't it be better...
if it had something new to it?
But they'll probably go hard...
with big, aggressive moves and things like that.
I feel like they'll make whole choreography like a picture.
Koo Young is strong at building those compositions.
But that might actually work against them.
Really hard choreography...
in my opinion, BADA's choreography...
will probably be very intense.
But it's also the kind that shines most on BADA.
So TAEYONG might look at it and think...
"That only shines when BADA does it."
I think there's a chance that could happen.
I don't think he'll want moves...
that need too much force.
Rather than moves that feel too fixed...
I think he'll want something that follows the groove...
with a few key accents.
When I was making the draft video for "WYLD,"
half of it was freestyle.
Only NaiN can say that because...
I brought in NaiN, who worked with him recently.
It's something only NaiN can say.
We really have to win.
You know better than anyone how badly I want this.
BADA and Koo Young have had such great results so far...
so maybe it's time for them to stumble once.
Absolutely.
We'll reveal which director has each section on the other team.
So it's divided by parts.
I had a feeling BABYZOO would take the intro.
Jun Hee got the pre-chorus. Front and back.
So NaiN leads, and BABYZOO...
Supports her?
It would be nice to have the whole framework first.
Yes.
The chorus is the most important part to make first.
So NaiN will take the chorus.
Leave it to me.
My choreography is trendy and loose but it still has that cool factor.
I can make it fit TAEYONG really well.
I'm confident.
What does TAEYONG like?
(This?)
But I'm hesitant to use big arm swings...
because it feels too similar to the choreography of "WYLD."
I want to give him something new.
What should I bring to him?
(Agonizing)
What could it be?
How well we match his taste is really important.
Something that can move TAEYONG.
We need that strategy.
NaiN, you'll find something that just clicks.
- Right, right.
- This!
I'll just throw out a bunch of ideas.
- "Wak."
- Since it's "Wak, Wak, Wak"...
If it's "Wak," then...
It means, "It's not great."
Right. Gross.
Or something like this?
(In perfect sync)
- This is pretty good.
- You are good.
That's nice.
And the head move is good too.
(Turning the head)
(Loving it)
We got it!
I thought the key was...
how to make the chorus fun and interesting.
Swinging the hands from side to side...
If we find one thing...
that instantly clicks, I think that's a success.
I'm absolutely sure about this.
I think TAEYONG would do this really well.
And I feel like BADA would do something like...
(What would BADA do for the chorus?)
I feel like she'd go for something like this.
(Laughing)
Or this.
(Possessed by BADA)
I feel like she'd do something like this.
I think she will hit it like this.
- Right? Stop, stop.
- Yes.
(What's BADA's intro chorus move?)
(Stop)
(Just as NaiN and BABY ZOO predicted)
Where were you working on?
Right here in front.
A-A-waka-wak
The song itself is full of swag and really fast...
but what's a point move...
that the public would like?
(For the chorus,)
(you can't ignore challenges.)
He brought up challenges himself...
and I also wanted to make...
something more approachable.
The image I have for Chorus One is...
"Wak" is kind of like... "You're all wack."
"I'm this. You're all wack."
(In that sense)
(Wack)
A forehead flick?
Is there anyone in Korea who can't flick a forehead?
I think anyone could do it easily.
I want to make this forehead-flick dance work.
To be completely honest...
(A forehead flick dance?)
I kept wondering how to make it work.
(The next day, they practice with the dancers.)
(The forehead flick attack makes the dancers fall.)
(Satisfied)
He said the dancers at the back...
would all fall back like this.
So I thought, "That could be fun."
Because what I wanted was...
a strong contrast between...
TAEYONG and everyone around him.
(Top tier TAEYONG's forehead flick)
He only needs to do this.
The dancers can provide all the energy.
Once we practiced with dancers, I became sure of it.
I think Koo Young's killing part...
is probably the forehead-flick dance.
Wak, wak, wak, wak, wak.
I wonder who made that part. Maybe Jun Hee?
(Wack-a-wak?)
He's a Waacker.
(Did Koo Young guess correctly?)
If I do this, people will criticize me...
for adding waacking moves again.
You know?
NaiN had such precise data about TAEYONG,
so I decided to refrain from adding my identity,
while reflecting her opinions more.
That way, I could pick...
the wow points that I liked.
I haven't...
(TAEYONG mentioned a flamboyant choreography.)
(He understands.)
BABYZOO does...
such a good job of painting with his body.
(TAEYONG approved of his arranging ability.)
In the intro...
(He had come up with the intro routine.)
(While practicing with the actual dancers,)
(he tried the intro routine that he came up with.)
BABYZOO is...
known in the industry...
to do a great job of arranging the wow points...
in K-pop songs.
No one can stop us.
But...
K-pop in this song?
(Sharp movements)
It doesn't suit this song.
This song is supposed to be performed on stages.
You have to be able to play.
There should be energy and krumping.
But I believed that strong movements...
might harm the song.
I expect the other team...
to focus on theatrical staging.
(Directing the intro)
Did you really call everyone else wack?
That's right.
BABYZOO...
and Jo Na In!
The intro will be...
like a press conference.
Everyone else...
is wack.
(TAEYONG stirred up trouble by calling people wack.)
(A press conference is held, and reporters come rushing in.)
A word, please.
Then, TAEYONG will...
(But TAEYONG doesn't care how others react.)
(A word? You're all wack!)
(He throws the microphone away and starts dancing.)
I believe our dance was more intense.
That could harm the song.
TAEYONG doesn't prefer meaningless highlights.
The artist picks it...
in the end.
The artist has to look cool...
when he does the dance.
We approached it with sensitivity and detail.
We came here for a reason.
We're both good at creating choreography.
We have the great choreographer from SM Entertainment.
And another choreographer from SM...
who's trying to follow in his footsteps.
Our chance of winning?
Probably 99 percent.
It's so obvious that we'll win this time,
but we want to win by a landslide.
(Which will TAEYONG pick?)
Their pride is on the line.
Except for MIN JUN,
they're the people who do this professionally.
I hope we do well.
If we lose,
we're done in this industry.
It's my profession, after all.
There's no way...
we're losing this.
(BAILEY's matchup: INGYOO and Simeez versus Kasper and MIN JUN)
(MIN JUN and Kasper's first meeting)
(The two listen to music without speaking.)
I never thought of working with Kasper,
and I didn't know him that well.
They've proven themselves,
and they're famous.
I guess they didn't pick me...
because they thought...
I was incompetent in the K-pop industry.
I thought...
I might be a burden to Kasper.
It was unsettling and difficult.
I'll do my best.
I'm just too worried.
No, I'm not worried about you.
Not at all.
I'm...
- No.
- worried, though.
Don't even think that.
As the missions went on,
he was the only one who constantly picked Hash.
It wasn't enough to convince me.
I don't think he utilized...
every dancer's character.
It's the Title Sequence Film Mission,
and the quality is ambiguous.
What about you, then?
He used to criticize me too.
So, I thought our preferences might be different.
I was worried...
that he wouldn't like me.
I believe...
you have a unique color...
that only you can show and no one else can.
For instance, I've been working with solo artists for too long.
TAEMIN, BAEKHYUN,
LAY, KEY,
and everyone.
I've only been working with them...
(Acting cocky again)
I directed their themes...
and even their outfits.
The cover of the album, how many we're going to release...
and which contractor we'll pick...
I couldn't fully trust him,
but if he was telling the truth,
he must have lots of data about this.
I thought I should believe him.
My trust in Kasper...
went from 0 to 40 percent...
after listening to him.
We need something that BAILEY wants.
In the end,
if the artist wants it,
that's it.
It's our job to make it that way.
I think it's impossible to lose to them.
Arrangements?
INGYOO and Hee Jung are...
so sure they're good at dance arrangement,
but that's my best quality.
And we have to win...
to make this more interesting.
That's true. It'll be interesting if those two go to the Last Stage.
Simeez, INGYOO, BADA, and Koo Young.
These four have to go to the Last Stage to make it fun.
If you go to the Last Stage twice, it's boring.
- I'm serious.
- It'll be boring for me too.
I don't think I can lose to them.
I'm the one who's been making the artists shine from behind.
I'm definitely going to win.
(Laughing)
I'm teaming up with Simeez.
I'm certain we'll win.
I've created choreography with him a few times.
I worked on "The Rizzness" by TAEMIN with him.
He's the best choreographer.
I think he makes them the most eye-catching...
among male choreographers.
I'm in charge of IVE from Starship Entertainment...
from the pre-production stage.
I have that experience.
We're going to win this.
(This is Simeez.)
Hang on.
(Falling)
(Laughing)
(What happened to INGYOO and Simeez?)
- Come outside.
- I wish I could.
Our main theme is...
- Do you know what Hydra is?
- I do.
It's a monster in Greek mythology.
She gives off that aura.
Hydra is the symbol of immortality and evolution.
They say Hydra is close to a systematic catastrophe.
But I feel like a systematic catastrophe...
is what BAILEY wants.
The appearance of a character that's never been here before.
You know, people call it...
a monster rookie.
Someone that never dies.
After all, the title is "Can't Kill Me."
The theme is a monster that only grows stronger...
every time you try to kill it.
In the intro,
Hydra Queen goes...
(Simeez will direct the intro.)
Before its birth,
and it's born.
(Was it successful?)
I wanted to express its transformation.
And we push.
I bet BAILEY wants...
to do something she's never done before.
If I were the artist,
I would want something that no K-pop choreographer has done.
But it has to be recognized by people,
while having a kick,
while being able to show off my abilities,
while being conceptual art,
while being the one and only.
I thought about it,
and I decided to use objets...
since I had experience.
(Ta-da)
We're in Dongdaemun...
to check out some fabric.
I wouldn't call it fabric.
I was thinking of a sort of film...
that sticks to your body.
Finding the right material isn't as it looks.
If we go with white, we can paint veins on it.
If we go with black, it'll set the mood.
(Simeez gives it a go.)
You're pretty.
(Laughing)
I like the red one.
Put it on.
I thought it would look more bizarre than black.
We'll use red fabric to express its birth.
I'm feeling it.
Look at me.
That's not bad. But if we're not careful,
it might look a bit funny.
(She tries dancing in the material.)
(Something like this?)
Not bad.
It's pretty. It's not that bad.
The performance that we have in mind is...
pretty conceptual.
I wanted to create a different image,
and I'm glad it came out well.
(They finally check the other team's section.)
That's how they did it?
We got something called Section Directors.
The first verse... At least it won't interrupt the flow.
The sections are largely divided.
It's a dance buildup.
I didn't expect MIN JUN to get the outro.
I thought Kasper would want the outro.
MIN JUN might do a good job.
I'm sure he will.
I wonder what he'll do.
I'm looking forward to seeing his outro.
When the sections were assigned,
there was a part...
that I was confident in.
Is there a section you really want?
The parts that I can clearly picture are...
the second verse...
- and the outro.
- Okay.
I have a clear picture in mind...
in terms of choreography.
The beat gets louder in the outro...
as they dance,
so I believe that's where his strength will shine.
- Before we meet tomorrow, - Yes.
let's complete most of it.
I don't know what your style is,
but I hate one-dimensional choreography.
I dislike nodding...
when you're supposed to nod in a part.
I'd like it to be a bit abstract.
(MIN JUN studies ALLDAY PROJECT's videos.)
K-pop isn't my strength,
so I can't decide.
I have to keep popularity in mind when I'm creating it.
I can't seem to come up with one.
My mind keeps going blank.
How far along are you?
(He can't seem to answer.)
I keep hitting a wall.
Show me the overall choreo,
thinking you're reminding yourself.
(MIN JUN shows him the pre-chorus that he came up with.)
It showed his inexperience.
I thought his feet were on fire.
He couldn't keep them still.
He was like...
(Fluttering and stomping)
He did the dance he did on his knees in the 1-on-1 Signature Mission...
only on his feet this time.
Here's what I think.
In the first "started" part,
it's quite similar to the one...
- you did in the first mission.
- Yes.
- You noticed it too, right?
That part could be...
I'll show you an example.
What was the exact dance?
Rather than going hard like this...
The outro, pre-chorus, and the chorus...
all looked the same.
I taught him...
which parts to leave out and how to change them...
on the spot.
Do you want to try the left hand?
Keep your right hand still.
(They keep revising the pre-chorus choreography.)
You can fully enjoy fried chicken if it's the only thing on the table.
But if there's fried chicken, tteokbokki,
jjajangmyeon, tangsuyuk,
and fried rice,
you can't decide what to eat.
So, I went,
"MIN JUN, I think we should eat jjajangmyeon today."
"Eat this." That was what I did.
You're good.
- Thank you.
- It's good.
I was so worried.
I'm here for you.
The buildup looks way better, thanks to you.
I wasn't sure if my choreography was good or not...
because I didn't have much experience.
But he complimented me a lot.
(A thumbs-up)
It looks better with a different texture.
This is how we normally do it. We change it bit by bit.
He said I did a good job.
Not only did he trust me, he also supported me.
My trust in him is up to 70 percent now.
This mission is practically what I do for a living,
so I can never lose.
It's what he does for a living?
What I'm doing is what I do for a living.
It was all thanks to the artist?
("like JENNIE" would have been a success,)
(no matter who directed it.)
He thought wrong.
I'm going to prove him wrong this time.
(Who will win in the end?)
There are so many new clothes, Na In.
They renew them every time.
It's what we wore yesterday.
For the draft proposal?
I could move really well in it when I danced.
It's cool.
Did they have these short jeans?
This screams, "BABYZOO."
- I can wear it on top of pants.
- Totally.
Is this what the other team wore?
Yes.
(The windbreaker that BADA and Koo Young wore)
(I'll try it on too.)
It's cute.
Isn't it?
(Does it suit me?)
You started dancing out of nowhere.
(He's excited because it looks good on him.)
(In love with himself)
There's one that I've been dying to wear.
- This one.
- I like it.
(The windbreaker that Na In picked)
This is yours.
(How do I look?)
Cute.
(I love it.)
It's pretty loose.
Like that?
(She tightens the hem drawstring.)
I like it.
That's a good point.
(It even goes well with the choreography.)
Nice.
Now that we have done some shopping,
why don't we move on to the next mission?
- All right.
- Let's go.
(Good luck, stylish NaiN and BABYZOO.)
Let's get some practice.
I just need to complete the outro and come up with a bridge.
We'll film the draft based on those.
Here's my idea for the second verse.
I wanted to play with the lyrics.
I had already come up with the second verse,
but I didn't want to stop his passion.
So, I decided...
to let him do what he wanted.
My sections are the second verse,
the 2nd pre-chorus, the 2nd chorus, and the outro.
That's how I made the dance for the second verse.
Stay here,
and you come down as you shake.
(Dancing hard)
Is this a prank?
(Laughing)
Kind of like Lady Gaga.
(Okay.)
If all our angles line up,
it will look pretty cool. That was my imagination.
Do we move our elbows or not?
Keep your elbows still, and only use your wrists.
- Just our wrists?
- Yes.
It was a new type of choreography.
But...
Seven, eight, and...
(Confused with the timing)
Six, seven, eight, and one. I guess it's this.
- Yes.
- Eight, and one.
That's how you do it.
It'd be great if you came all the way here.
- If not, we can form...
- We can.
two lines.
Sorry, this wasn't the formation that I had in mind.
(Hesitant)
Three...
(He can't give them clear directions.)
He seemed to lack confidence.
He also seemed unsure.
- Inside...
- If you want to stick to it...
Yes?
I don't think Ye Hwan and I should be the ones...
coming forward while grabbing their shoulders.
- It should be these two.
- Okay.
Kasper mostly led practice.
I know that I should show them a cool choreography...
and be able to lead them...
as a director,
but it didn't go my way.
I'm upset that I failed to give them detailed directions.
(Simeez and INGYOO's draft shoot)
(Simeez and INGYOO rehearse before the shoot.)
(Simeez plays BAILEY, the artist,)
(and WE DEM BOYZ is the dance team for the draft?)
If I were BAILEY's director,
I would never put a female dancer next to her.
I agree. I'd rather put her there by herself.
But I'm concerned...
that no male dancer can do this type of dance.
You're looking for a wild man.
I need Vata to do it.
AHOB is pretty good at that too. You know, wild movements.
Kamel's good too.
He crawls around like a dog.
(They practice the 2nd pre-chorus...)
(after the 1st verse.)
(The heels won't come off easily.)
It's the part where the artist takes her heels off.
She couldn't take them off.
She has to hand over the microphone,
take her heels off,
and the microphone has to go around and return to her.
The timing was off.
Get the microphone!
I wasn't so sure it would work.
You have to move your heels with your right hand...
as fast as possible...
so that you can get the microphone with your left hand.
Show the first heel...
and take off the second heel fast.
(You think I don't know that?)
And don't stand in the front for too long.
Take one heel off, and move to the back.
I can't because they're still passing.
Oh, no. Hang on.
My feet are too sweaty to take them off.
I see.
There were some tiring parts.
I had to wear heels,
and we wasted a lot of time doing the lift.
(The outro lift is another tricky part.)
It looks funny because...
(It looks limp after pointing her toes.)
This is funny.
I want it to look stronger when you touch it.
I don't think...
the touching part should be intense.
This is the highlight.
- I can't see that.
- Why not?
Because we didn't do it properly...
or you just couldn't see it?
I played the artist,
so I couldn't...
look at the whole choreography from outside.
I had to be her eyes...
because she was playing the artist.
I tried to keep a cool head and didn't give up.
I told her,
"That doesn't look right. We have to go farther."
(Trying the intro...)
(where she hangs inside the fabric.)
I felt the limit in the intro.
I was upside down, and...
Good. Come down.
Their feet kept slipping because of the cloth,
so the three of them held me only with their arm strength.
This is full of risks.
Our performance is very risky.
It would have been fine if we were only using our bodies.
I'm concerned that we may not...
complete the perfect draft.
Get ready.
Set it up.
- Fog!
- Let's start.
All right, MIN JUN.
- Let's go!
- Get set.
- All right.
In the intro,
we expressed a snake hanging on a tree.
There's moonlight and thick fog.
The first part is what sets the mood for the whole song,
so it's very important.
Kasper looked certain about the performance.
I decided to trust him since he was so sure.
MIN JUN tries hard to follow my lead,
and I also try hard to reflect his opinions.
- It looks good.
- I tried to be quick...
with the decisions.
Great work, guys.
- Good job.
- Great job.
I'm positive we'll win.
(Simeez and INGYOO take a long time to film.)
One, two...
(The microphone keeps getting in the way,)
(and there are mistakes with the props.)
I started getting worried...
that our goal was too ideal...
and that we might not be able to reach it.
It doesn't looks so pretty when it's sticking out.
I think you should be sitting on the fabric.
- Do you get what I mean?
- I knew that.
But I just went with it because it was dangerous.
Let's go with this one. Let's move on.
I don't think we have it yet.
To be honest, I didn't like any of it.
What is it that you want?
I'm still scared when I'm hanging upside down.
- That's true.
- From here...
I was exhausted and pressured,
so I started getting sensitive.
I didn't want to make it obvious,
but we both have our unique styles,
and they were too different.
I guess I kind of snapped...
because it felt too different all of a sudden.
I regretted it a bit.
Maybe I should have been more considerate.
She was dancing on heels...
for hours and showing her tenacity.
It was impressive.
Should we go again?
- Okay.
- Let's do it.
- We're almost there.
- Let's go!
- You've got this!
Even though it was risky,
I wanted to show her...
how much we could help her achieve her dream.
It's totally perfect.
I was watching, and she eventually surprised me.
So, I thought, "This is it!"
That was the one.
Great work!
(Their shoot took 12 hours.)
I couldn't wait to see her perform...
the choreography that INGYOO and I created.
We have to win.
All right.
I don't think I've ever worked on a draft...
wishing so hard...
that they would pick ours.
(Desperate)
Hello.
(They have another meeting with TAEYONG.)
Hi.
(Giggling)
It's so awkward.
(Who's sitting next to him?)
(He's been in charge of NCT's numerous performances.)
(Choreographer Lee Il Hyeong has worked...)
(on numerous performances by TAEYONG.)
- Right?
- I expect it to be intense.
I know.
(The two teams will compete section by section.)
Winning in the chorus section is better for the choreographers...
because having to choreograph the chorus...
is easier to make their names known.
But I believe that a choreographer and a director are...
two different roles.
From a director's perspective,
it doesn't matter which section you get.
You should be able to make the artist shine whichever it is.
Also, the chorus isn't the only part that goes viral.
Whether it's the verse or the intro,
there's a possibility that it goes viral.
I honestly think that every section matters now.
But if I were the choreographer,
I would be prouder to know...
that I choreographed the chorus.
It would make me feel good.
(That's true.)
We're coming in.
- Hello.
- Hi.
As soon as I saw him, I wasn't even nervous.
I just thought it'd be fun. I was confident.
I reckoned that TAEYONG would prefer ours.
Today, we'll watch...
the draft videos of each team.
First, NaiN and BABYZOO.
Okay.
NaiN, I'll give them the proposal.
- It's...
- Here you go.
- Yes. This is ours.
- Thank you.
Look at all those words.
(Packed)
I thought that...
there was a bit too much written on the sheet.
- Hello!
I'm Choreographer NaiN.
I'm Choreographer BABYZOO.
(Full of expectation)
She was the choreographer...
in charge of TAEYONG.
She was on my mind...
as she knew what TAEYONG wanted.
I predicted the choreography...
to come out neat.
But this time,
being neat doesn't seem to suit the energy of the song.
We thought about the keyword of the song.
We wanted to focus on "top tier."
It isn't a competition with the others.
It's the feeling that others are trying to catch up.
We wanted to express...
being on another level.
We were on the same line.
NaiN's team emphasized superiority.
That was also our focus.
Instead of doing a long explanation,
we wanted to reveal the video right away.
We'll play the video first...
and explain afterward!
That's confidence!
(Team NaiN and BABYZOO's draft video gets revealed.)
The intro was disappointing.
I thought it would be a lot more eye-catching.
When the intro started,
I didn't feel a great impact.
For the intro chorus, we didn't follow the lyrics.
We made a new rhythm to make an impact.
I thought that the overall balance...
felt slightly feminine.
That's impressive.
We worked with the rap rhymes in Verse One...
and created key moves.
(Impressed)
It was a simple structure,
but they added wow points.
I was impressed by them.
We thought...
It was cool.
I like how the moves were expressed using the whole body.
The pre-chorus was disappointing.
The part felt...
less energetic than the other parts.
To express the song's strong vibes,
we put in the signature choreography.
I thought that the simple moves...
were expressed in a classy way.
I thought that TAEYONG liked what he saw.
I feel satisfied.
Gosh, the overall setup...
is insane.
The setup that made the artist stand out...
felt like a threat.
The pre-chorus moves were simple,
but we worked on the overall setup...
by focusing on the formation and timing.
Gosh!
For Chorus Two,
we wanted to hit the climax...
with the energy of the dancers.
(You can watch their full video on "The CHOOM" and "Mnet Plus.")
Gosh, that was so exciting.
I got surprised.
TAEYONG seemed to be really satisfied.
They did a great job.
They were a big threat.
I had no regrets about the final result.
I feel like we can...
find the right outfit for the artist.
I feel confident.
I'll explain some of the interesting parts.
In Chorus One,
we placed this signature move.
This is the meaning behind it.
With authority and control,
there's no need to take action.
The one in the "top tier" position doesn't need to do anything.
We wanted to visualize the image of...
not being bothered about competing the others.
Throughout the choreography,
there's a part where something is crumpled up...
and thrown out to the side.
We added significance to that part.
As for the killing part,
we thought about what could express being the top of the top.
A simple way to express it was by going up.
When you went up and down,
you look relaxed while having fun,
but the other dancers were doing strong moves.
That point was the greatest way...
to express the difference in position.
We tried our best...
to make TAEYONG, the top-tier artist,
stand out as much as possible.
Actually, I'm never like that in real life.
(Flustered)
"Was this the wrong approach? What do we do?"
"Okay. What a relief."
But...
there's a certain image...
that people dream about being in a top-tier position.
If I express this image to the viewers as an artist,
it will become a great way to quench their thirsts...
of this desire.
"What?"
It was an unexpected response.
I felt the energy of becoming a top-tier artist.
It also...
made me relieve a lot of stress.
"Oh, my gosh."
"Gosh, we're doomed."
It relieved his stress.
That meant he was satisfied.
I thought that...
we made a great approach.
With the parts that had to express the lyrics,
we tried to make the parts look straightforward.
For example...
(The part with the V sign matched with the lyrics)
We thought of ways...
to make these parts stand out.
I'm a big lover...
of the V sign.
(That's awesome.)
(Pro V sign user, TAEYONG)
The whole world is on our side!
We went with the V sign since it was in the lyrics.
He happened to like the V sign!
It was unexpected.
We didn't know that part of him to be able to utilize that.
I'm a big lover of the V sign.
I add it to my lyrics often.
I thought that it was creative.
It wasn't a simple usage of the V sign.
I loved how they played around with the rhythm.
BABYZOO, you're great with coming up with structures.
Verse Two felt visually attractive and memorable.
- Thank you.
- And...
as for NaiN, your dancing is amazing.
Should I call it spot on?
It's very powerful.
You two seem to be a great match.
"This isn't good for us."
He seemed to be really satisfied.
He looked happy about it.
I'm certain that he will choose ours.
I have no doubt about it.
Based on the draft video,
the short and important parts...
- will be described through the app.
- Right.
We went with a showy formation of the dancers...
to make an impact.
As for the outfit,
we wanted red to be the key color.
You mentioned something shiny.
I want something bling bling.
I want a lot of shiny outfits.
(Keeping note of shiny outfits)
You mentioned something shiny.
We thought that enamel would suit you well.
We wanted to make the outfit itself...
to make you look powerful.
- These are the dancers' outfits.
- Right.
They have gloves.
Including the signature move,
there are many moves that use the hands.
We chose the gloves...
thinking that they would stand out even from a distance.
The dancers will wear bandanas.
- Really?
- Yes.
They're going to feel really hot.
"Oh, no!"
It's okay.
It's to keep our concept and style.
(Laughing)
She said, "It's okay."
(That's cute.)
I felt so flustered.
This is the reason behind the bandanas.
We didn't want the artist and dancers to reveal their faces.
We wanted to create a contrast even with this aspect.
That was the idea behind this decision.
There's a strategy of covering up the dancers...
and making the artist stand out completely.
This is a method...
that agencies prefer using for solo artists.
In that aspect,
they did a good job to utilize that.
Right.
Hello. This is...
- Koo Young!
- And BADA!
- Koo and BA!
- Let's lure TAEYONG!
(Let's go, Koo and BA!)
For this draft, BADA...
took TAEYONG's role.
I expected that decision.
I thought that BADA's dancing...
would be utilized.
I expected a strong impact from BADA.
But I also believed that impact...
might go against them.
Here's a brief explanation of our song interpretation.
This performer is full of self-belief.
His thoughts and characteristics are expressed without hesitation...
and he freely crushes the stage.
This is the character we went with.
Nothing felt like a threat based on the concept.
This was the idea we had...
with the dancers.
We focused on making it feel like a grand festival or grand concert.
A concert?
That was when I thought...
something was wrong about it.
He was going to make a comeback in music shows in September.
"A concert? A mega crew?"
I was confused by their concept.
As you're a global idol,
- Global?
- we tried to match that level.
This is the killing part...
that will take over this summer and fall.
It's the finger flick move.
Finger flick?
We prepared the finger flick move.
- You will see it in the video.
- Right.
Got it.
- I won't talk about it too much.
- Right.
I couldn't imagine what it would be like.
They're great at creating point moves.
That was a threat against us.
It's time!
Let's go!
Let's watch the video!
The intro was the complete opposite of ours.
The intro was simple,
but I liked the energy that could be felt.
Good!
I thought that it looked nice...
because it was BADA doing the dancing.
Gosh!
We really wanted to express...
the lyrics in Verse One.
The hands were used a lot in order to do that.
The rap went by quickly,
but it was disappointing to see just the use of hands.
There were acting parts in between.
I liked the parts where the artist could freely express himself.
The bass line in the background felt like an engine.
We wanted to express an engine overheating.
Will that finger flick move...
be able to take over this summer?
The repetitive moves...
felt quite disappointing.
Verse Two...
didn't have a same pattern.
We wanted to create a taste that could make him stand out.
I liked the sound of the siren.
I liked how the formation looked really neat.
We wanted the dancers to move under TAEYONG's orders.
We wanted to create a part that could express...
the energy and atmosphere of victory.
There's jumping in both drafts.
Right. There's jumping in both.
The rhythm feels similar as well.
Overall,
it was hard to see the flow.
(You can watch their full video on "The CHOOM" and "Mnet Plus.")
(Totally satisfied)
(Koo and BA are satisfied as well.)
I thought that our draft matched the energy of the song...
and had a greater impact.
I was 10,000 percent sure that TAEYONG would choose ours.
Our draft felt like a better outfit...
for TAEYONG.
If more dancers are added,
it will become greater in scale.
I believe it will look a lot more open.
- Right.
A total of 13 dancers will get added to this.
We will perform in a larger group on the 25th.
We will be in danger if they do a good job with that.
That part felt like a threat.
The first part was an expression...
of confidence without any hiding.
"I'm confident about myself."
This was what we wanted to express.
The mics appeared.
The flashlights of the phones were used as well.
I wondered if those things...
would match the weight of his image.
This will become a hit this summer.
It stings just by watching.
This is a challenge...
that all members in the office can pull off.
The fingers are made into a W.
- The ring finger is used.
- The ring finger?
Right. A W is made with the fingers. This part can become a challenge.
"How is this a finger flick? I don't really get it."
All you did was a simple finger flick,
but the others collapse by the impact.
- Should we do a demonstration?
- Sure.
(Totally excited)
"Is that necessary?"
We had to make the finger flick move stand out.
He mentioned wanting to start a challenge.
(During the first meeting)
(With the chorus,)
(I wish for it to become a challenge.)
We had to fulfill the needs of the artist.
TAEYONG seemed to like the finger flick move.
It felt great.
"Would people really want to copy the finger flick move?"
This was what I thought.
As for the chorus,
we came up with the W hand gesture...
that represents "Wack."
It was obvious that this was a W...
even without an explanation.
There had to be an interesting part to it,
but I felt that it wasn't that charming.
The sense of something coming up with "Wack."
- "Wack."
- We used that feel...
to create the performance.
The last chorus...
is a big explosion. The whole stage is taken over.
The audience will be on the side instead of being underneath.
- The audience will join in...
- I see.
and the dancers will go up on the poles and do a headbang.
The energy on the stage.
(Laughing)
We focused a lot...
on how the artist would connect with the audience.
That part definitely stands out from the choreography.
TAEYONG wanted to make a good performance...
with the audience.
He wanted to show his excitement on stage.
It felt like he was going to prefer our performance.
The sound gets turned off toward the end.
- Right.
- The sounds are removed.
"Okay. I don't want to hear any sound."
"I want silence." We wanted to express this vibe.
As for the outfit,
there's a point move that uses quick steps.
To emphasize those steps,
we thought it was a great idea to use "Wacka Wak."
- Right.
- These are rhinestones.
We thought it would be great to go with this design.
These outfits were seen often.
The stage will look like this...
with the dancers.
"Wacka Wak..."
will constantly be shown through the LED display.
"Wacka Wak" will be the only thing they think about after it ends.
We tried to make everyone focus on TAEYONG only.
- Right.
- That's all from us!
- Thank you!
- "Wacka Wak!"
("Wacka Wak!")
When we ended our presentation,
TAEYONG did this.
"Our W gesture..."
"must be stuck inside his head."
After seeing that,
I felt a rush of adrenaline.
I believe we have a great chance of winning.
TAEYONG really liked our V sign.
Doesn't that mean the game is over?
I strongly believe that he will choose our draft.
Hello.
We came today...
with a great sense of determination.
To be honest, I didn't have anything to worry about.
We're quite far away from each other.
I wanted to present it quickly.
We're talented in creating universes.
I felt confident about our performance.
"What did they come up with?"
I was certain that...
our performance would suit BAILEY more than theirs.
I was curious about theirs.
(Relaxed)
We didn't feel that much threat from them.
I wondered...
what they would say after seeing ours.
- Let's go!
- Hello!
- Hi! Hello!
- Hey!
Yo! Oh, my gosh!
Look at you guys! How are you doing?
It was tough for us.
You're the star.
I can't kill you guys.
- Okay.
Okay. As you guys know,
the draft videos will get revealed today.
And I'm really looking forward to them. Genuinely.
- Oh, my gosh!
- Gosh!
I did feel worried as we had to meet her expectations.
I was confident...
because I knew what her strengths were.
I came up with a tailor-made suit.
Team MIN JUN and Kasper...
- Good luck!
- will go first.
The video will be shown first instead of a long explanation.
We tried our best while thinking about...
your greatest strengths.
Thank you.
Won't Kasper and MIN JUN focus on the dancing?
Kasper isn't someone with great concepts.
I didn't know what to expect from MIN JUN,
but I knew Kasper's style of work.
I didn't expect something feminine from them.
(Team JEONG MIN JUN and Kasper's draft video gets revealed.)
What?
Kasper and I must've had similar ideas.
It's better for us as ours will stand out more.
The intro.
It was the first scene that started the mood of the song.
We focused on dreamlike vibes.
It's really similar to our part.
I came up with BAILEY's...
first signature move.
I think he knows my style.
There were many body control parts.
The repetitive parts felt nice.
For Chorus One,
we designed a solo part.
We came up with this part...
thinking that she was the only one who could pull this off.
It lacked impact.
Why a solo part out of nowhere?
The part felt too long...
and it made it feel empty.
Verse Two focuses on the lyrics.
I think the symmetry is really pretty.
And it kind of makes me feel the fullness of the song.
And for Pre-Chorus 2 and Chorus 2,
there's a rhythm-making part.
We wanted to make a catchy part that people would remember.
MIN JUN's parts looked similar.
I could see BAILEY...
with the choreography.
But with the overall flow...
It was a nonstop sequence of movements.
It was difficult to pinpoint...
a clear theme of the choreography.
I composed the bridge with a bit more feminine movements.
But I couldn't miss out on the musicality.
It's unfortunate.
As for both MIN JUN and Kasper,
they're not used to dancing with a feminine touch.
It seemed that...
they didn't have a good understanding of her style.
So their choreography left a lot to be desired.
The outro has a lot of bold beats.
I wanted them to be more explosive.
The choreography for the outro is broken down into small, quick moves.
There are many moments where things could just blow up.
That's crazy.
(You can watch their full video on "The CHOOM" and "Mnet Plus.")
(Giving them a round of applause)
(Glancing over)
I was like, "What's going on?"
It was hard to tell whether or not she liked it.
She's so good at keeping a poker face.
It was impossible to read her at all.
I thought it was an either-or situation.
She either loves it or hates it.
We had some similar moves.
It was bound to happen because of the lyrics.
They had a similar mood and flow.
But they didn't have a clear concept that left an impression.
Their performance was predictable.
Their performance primarily focused on dancing.
They didn't have any wow factor or impress us with the routine.
So I knew we had this in the bag.
Oh, my.
What did you think?
So much information.
(Nervous)
I'm definitely going to have to keep watching that.
Dissecting it and digging it a little bit.
Is this a good thing?
Or a bad thing?
I was worried.
She might be in a different mood.
And her style might be different too.
If she's going to keep watching that...
When she said she had to analyze it,
that feedback didn't sound positive.
It sounded more like she didn't know...
what kind of feedback she should give them.
First of all,
we only focused on your strength...
and came up with this choreography.
So we didn't want to bring in any of that diva energy because...
you can only pull off certain performances at a specific age.
I thought he had it completely wrong.
Every female artist has a fantasy...
of becoming a diva on stage.
He was completely off here.
I thought this was the moment that decided the outcome.
I didn't think that...
she could embody the queen vibe.
She's too young to pull that off.
I wanted to show the world...
who she was with this choreography.
The performance keyword we conveyed...
with our routine was...
the albino snake.
Albino snakes are...
different from other snakes.
But being different doesn't mean...
there's something wrong with them.
We wanted to convey that this difference was special
In the intro, you're hanging upside down from a tree.
I tried to picture you as an albino snake...
when I composed the intro.
In Verse One,
the dark energy is pulling you in.
"I don't care."
You're facing a lot of hardships, but they don't get to you.
That's what I had in mind for this part.
For Pre-Chorus One,
you're known for your hand gestures.
I really loved this part.
Really? Thank you.
Hearing such comments makes me so happy.
I came up with a move that could represent her style.
And she said she really liked that.
I could tell that he spent a lot of time analyzing her style.
He practically tailored this choreography for her.
There were a few parts...
where he added hand gestures...
BAILEY would be satisfied with.
But I need to take a closer look to see if they made sense...
with the story and the overall choreography.
And it was just a nonstop sequence of movements for the rest.
"I'm so good."
When you're showing off with 40 consecutive moves,
people get sick of it.
When the song flows into the outro,
this is where you're going to blow it up.
We came up with the sequence that was perfect for the ending.
You're declaring victory...
or telling people you'll win.
We focused on "You can't kill me."
This concept aligns with the move of shooting a gun with eyes covered.
We wanted to convey that vibe.
That's quite deep.
The whole story is deep.
I think it is important.
I think killing parts having moments that are memorable are important...
with the right intention.
I think a lot of times now it's very...
We think we have to do something to get people going.
You know? But if it's unnatural,
I feel like I can feel that just as a creative person.
None of it feels forced, though.
Which I really appreciate here.
I was relieved.
I was anxious.
I think in the very beginning...
with this tree situation...
It just automatically wowed me.
Right from the beginning... "Oh, my gosh. What am I looking at?"
I think that's definitely a big memorable part.
It was just as I thought.
We did give her something she really loved.
It's like we crafted a tailored suit for BAILEY.
We whipped up something she'd love and served it to her.
Satisfying BAILEY's needs as an artist?
That's a given.
We need to go a step beyond that...
and level it up.
Let's go, Team B.
- Team B.
- What's up, B?
How are you doing?
I'm curious to see what the performance director...
of Jennie and IVE can do.
I think they might have come up...
with a similar concept.
Okay. Hold on.
The concept is about...
Hydra Queen.
(Silent)
What's this? Is he feeling okay?
Hold on. Did I mess this up?
Gosh. This isn't what we expected. Something was off.
- Do you know Hydra?
- Hydra?
Yes. Hydra is...
like a monster.
(A monster?)
A monster?
Did I hear that right?
Do you have pictures?
There. Boom.
Here you go.
Those were some grotesque-looking pictures.
He wants BAILEY to execute this concept?
There's a thin line between looking creepy...
and looking cool.
And it looked creepy.
Let me explain what she can do.
Even when her neck gets sliced,
it regenerates.
- I see. Okay.
- Yes.
The more she gets killed,
the stronger she becomes.
Let me explain how we came up with this concept.
If we were to measure...
the combat power of your dance,
this would happen.
So...
- What was that?
- She's already...
Did you prepare that?
(She fails to hold back her laughter.)
- What was that?
- She's already...
Did you prepare that?
No.
(Laughing)
It was embarrassing to watch him present.
I wanted to hide.
She's already a queen.
She's...
She's already Hydra Queen.
You know what it is, right?
- It's Son Goku's glasses.
- Gosh, he's just crazy.
Why is he so funny?
Yes. I know what you're saying.
I guess I won her over...
when I ambushed her with my little joke.
Actually, I wasn't trying to be funny.
I wanted to convey my concept.
But she liked it.
It didn't matter whether she laughed...
because she liked it or she found it ridiculous.
Laughing is good.
When we laugh, it puts us in a good mood.
Okay. Next.
We went with high heels.
With these heels...
and these styling elements,
we wanted to depict non-human aspects.
Bones are protruding out here.
We wanted to give you an outfit where it made you look combat ready.
So you're a queen in combat mode.
You know what I'm saying?
Let's go to the next slide.
(That's it.)
(Clapping)
Our presentation is compact.
What's he saying?
He moved on super fast.
"We want you to be a queen for our concept."
But anyone could've come up with that.
Their approach to this project...
felt predictable to me.
- Must we explain more?
- No.
Let's begin. Boom.
(Simeez and INGYOO reveal their performance video.)
(Curious)
The chance of having an identical sequence for the intro...
would be one in a million.
It was identical. I thought that was crazy.
What was crazier was that they were holding her up in the same pose.
I could tell that they were determined to win too.
It crossed my mind that we might end up with some same moves.
They must've thought that it was a groundbreaking move.
But it wasn't.
We were going for the imagery...
of a cocoon, wrapped in silk, for the intro.
We wanted to build suspense before the birth of a monster.
I wish the red wrap was prettier...
and stood out a little more.
It didn't look good at all.
So many thoughts.
He's going to hold the microphone like that?
That's something an amateur would come up with.
In Pre-Chorus One, we wanted to show the awakening...
of Hydra Queen, born as a completely different creature.
In the lyrics, the word, "gun," really stood out.
"You can't kill me."
To express that, she has to show her combativeness.
It's dark and a bit grotesque.
But it also has a feminine aspect with an alluring edge.
Just the color... It sticks so well.
For Verse Two, we wanted to stay on the beat...
and incorporate high heels into our routine.
The heels didn't look like an integral element.
It just looked like she was dancing in heels.
She wore heels. Then we should've been impressed...
by her routine.
But she was just a dancer in heels.
When she takes off the high heels in Pre-Chorus Two,
she breaks away from everything...
and turns into a monster.
We wanted to show that...
everyone has surrendered to her as she's the queen.
That was the storyline of our routine.
It's really cool.
Once the choreography comes together,
the synergy would blow up.
The real battle starts now. She's in combat mode.
- Combat mode.
- Okay.
Krump?
Krump isn't her thing.
He wants a female artist to krump barefoot?
On stage?
I thought she would be the only artist...
who could pull off krumping in a solo dance break.
The next part was really important..
So many things are happening in the outro. We went with a lift.
Everything would just blow up at the end.
(Impressed)
We tried to convey the combativeness...
and energy of the queen the best we could.
I thought all those micro-movements...
breaking down the beats...
were messy.
(You can watch their full video on "The CHOOM" and "Mnet Plus.")
Oh, my gosh.
Check out the look on her face.
It was no joke.
I did see them as a threat.
They used the red wrap, gloves,
and heels in their routine.
Their visual taste is spot on.
But they lacked any real choreography.
I thought it was just lame.
Simeez's use of the red wrap...
She's already done something similar at a showcase.
I thought everything was excessive.
The styling was too much. Hair and makeup were too much.
The concept was too much. And the choreography too.
The way she took off her heels looked silly.
There are so many techniques BAILEY can do with heels.
But she mostly gave BAILEY basic moves.
I was worried that it might offend BAILEY.
"This is all you can do with my skillset?"
We set Hydra Queen as our motif.
"Can't kill me." She can't be killed.
As for the intro, we had the same sequence.
It was identical. I was pretty shocked too.
In the intro, four dancers hold the red wrap...
and pull it down.
And it creates a visually striking scene...
and brings focus to Hydra Queen.
You'll rip it and come out at "started."
Before that part, I won't have a microphone with me?
The dancers are going to carry it.
We can definitely develop more regarding the microphone.
- There's a lot to develop.
- Yes.
I was quite shocked because it was really bad.
It looked silly to have a microphone here.
I get that the dancer is going to move the microphone.
But it doesn't look cool.
We were able to deliver the microphone to her.
It was done with precision and complete accuracy.
I thought it was irresponsible.
There's something I'm a little concerned about.
I'm afraid I might look like a fish.
Too much like a fish.
- Oh, that.
- Like a fish.
Don't worry about that.
We can only pick out cool-looking ones.
We can pick out only the good ones...
- and narrow them down.
- Okay.
Don't worry.
Even she thought it was pretty lame.
"Do I really have to do that? Do I have to become a fish?"
She'll have to compromise her looks for this choreography.
Is this worth her trouble?
I don't think it is.
This wasn't a one-time thing, was it?
I thought she was going to use this for every performance.
I just didn't understand where their confidence came from.
You'll ditch the heels. Actually,
- you can freestyle here.
- Yes.
Unlike any other artists,
you can fully freestyle on stage.
My gosh.
When I heard that they wanted her to freestyle for the second chorus,
I gave up trying to understand their concept.
They're just leaving everything up to her.
She's going to take that risk and perform this song on stage?
I don't think that's possible.
After hearing everything, I can see it super clear...
even with stage things.
I think that the use of heels is very memorable...
because at least from a non-dancer's point of view...
"Oh, that's like that heel thing."
You can kind of click that with something.
I think those little moments are a really strong part of me.
It feels like maybe, there's a little bit...
more room that we can go with that.
Is it going to turn into a gun? Or it is going to...
I feel like we can use a little bit more.
I got the feeling that she focused a lot on the heels.
I thought we were going in the right direction.
Her feedback sounded like she was planning...
to perform this choreography.
Okay. Well, I have a lot of thinking to do.
But I think I genuinely want to thank you...
for making it this difficult for me.
So I will...
(She has a lot on her mind.)
work things through.
Really. Truly. Thank you so much. I'll see you guys at the rehearsal.
Thank you.
- I feel confident.
- It looked like..
she wanted to dance in heels.
For a female artist to krump, it's a new challenge.
So I was certain she would love...
these groundbreaking elements.
They completely lacked in character understanding.
Let's say I bought a product. And I fully read the manual.
But they didn't.
I know...
how to maximize the use of this iPhone.
But they're clueless.
They only use it to make calls and watch YouTube.
I think she's going to pick us.
Two artists, BAILEY and TAEYONG,
watched both teams' videos.
Each artist will compare...
the choreography of the two teams for each section.
And they will pick...
the choreography of the team they prefer.
So I think it's kind of a choice...
of how to present myself at this moment.
Okay. Verse One. I think I have to go that way.
It's a tough call, but I'll go with this team.
- No? Did we pick a different team?
- What is it?
- I see. We went different ways.
- Really?
I really thought that...
our intro left a bigger impact on them.
If he's the TAEYONG I know,
he would definitely pick our intro.
I'm going to be nervous.
We poured our heart and soul into every scene.
We can't afford to lose.
"This part will look great."
"That part will be a great choice."
Wins and losses by section?
"I think we're going to win every section."
(The intro is the first step into the world.)
(Team JEONG MIN JUN and Kasper's killing part...)
(is the intro.)
(Section Director: Simeez, Section Director: Kasper)
(Both teams chose a similar concept for the intro.)
(I was certain.)
(I think MIN JUN and Kasper's intro...)
(It's perfect as it is right now.)
(On the other hand, with Team Simeez and INGYOO,)
(if I can kind of tweak things and changes things,)
(it could take a whole different direction.)
(She'll have to compromise her looks for this choreography.)
(Is this worth her trouble?)
(Intro Chosen by Artist BAILEY, Simeez and INGYOO)
(We're going in the right direction.)
(This is a huge risk.)
(Why did she go with them?)
(The main dish is the intro.)
(She okayed the main dish.)
(We can add extra rice or seasoned vegetables...)
(whenever we want.)
(I really wanted to work with you.)
(I dreamed of becoming a dancer since I was 16.)
(BAILEY is an artist...)
(who can also see performances in a director's point of view.)
(She doesn't need a director.)
(She can nail everything.)
(I'm a student right now.)
(I was nervous.)
(Do you think you can do this?)
(Executing it right away)
(His job satisfaction hits an all-time high.)
(Learning a new style of dancing)
(Observing)
(It's fun.)
(Actively generating results)
(His job satisfaction as an artist hits an all-time high.)
(Things are going well.)
(Actually, NaiN and BABYZOO's choreography is more fun.)
(It's easier to learn.)
(And the composition is interesting.)
(I think their choreography is well-polished.)
(On the rehearsal day with Team BADA and Back Koo Young,)
(TAEYONG looks conflicted.)
(I can't remember their choreography.)
(Take it easy.)
What was this thing?
(There are too many details to remember.)
(I told him to take it easy,)
(but I was so flustered.)
(Things were bound to get serious.)
(I wasn't sure if I could pull...)
(everything off.)
Like this.
(It's too hard.)
Dancing...
(Dancing this choreography is...)
(It's making me lose it.)
(I kept thinking that this might be too much on him.)
(He might think that we added a lot more gestures.)
(I wanted to skip a lot of them.)
(I'm the opposite.)
(I'd zero in on more details.)
(I would have tripled it.)
(I'm not sure.)
(Not for TAEYONG with ten years of experience.)
(Their opinions are divided right before the performance.)
(We did make a mistake.)
(I wouldn't go that far.)
(The two choreographers can't seem to reach an agreement.)
(D-Day of K-pop Solo Artist Direct Mission)
(Matchup for TAEYONG's Track)
(Matchup for BAILEY's Track)
(After watching the performances by both teams,)
(they'll vote for the one...)
(they want to see more as the official performance.)
(Which performance will win over the artists' fans?)
(Her fans will love this.)
(I was wondering if her fans would like our performance.)
(I bet BAILEY's fans...)
(are rooting for her from the bottom of their heart.)
(BAILEY's Going into the wrap...)
(Their performance was risky from start to finish.)
(Was risk their performance keyword?)
(What was the hardest part about their performance?)
(It was just so hectic.)
(It looks like it.)
(But we didn't compare ourselves to them.)
(It's not like I made things up.)
(They might be thinking about Last Stage.)
(If I were in the audience I would've thought...)
(Team NaiN and BABYZOO's performance looked cooler.)
(TAEYONG is great.)
(I bet he's going to like this performance.)
(What does TAEYONG think?)
(My face is more expressive here.)
(I look like I'm in control.)
(To choose one for the official stage performance,)
(the reaction from the fans is important too.)
(Didn't they scream more for that?)
(For the Solo Artist Direct Mission...)
(The final director of my official performance...)
(Who will be the final directors chosen by the artists?)
(Once again,)
(Last Stage will be held for their survival.)
(At the end of this performance,)
(three of the choreographers will survive,)
(and one of them will have to leave the stage.)
(Let's fully prepare ourselves for Last Stage.)
(I have 24 hours. I don't know what to do.)